Mayank C Koli

☐ Indian ○ Pitampura, New Delhi 110034, India ☐ +91-8826634734

(i) https://www.linkedin.com/in/mayankckoli (i) https://github.com/manukoli1986



Profile

Cloud & DevSecOps Specialist with strong skills in AWS, CI/CD, Kubernetes, Python and Terraform IAAC with over 10+ years of experience in planning, implementing and maintaining Infra, business applications and microservices in AWS, GCP and hybrid Cloud leveraging Configuration Management, Container Orchestration and

Continuous Integration tools.

Work experience

- Implemented a new cloud infrastructure for the customers, resulting in faster and more reliable service for customers
- Automated the provisioning of new development and test environments in the cloud, reducing the time to spin up.
- Implementing IAAC templates on AWS and its services like AWS IAM, VPC, EC2, RDS, S3, ELB, Auto Scaling, Route 53, Cloud Watch, Cloud Trail, SQS, SNS, Deploy, Code Build Code Pipeline and create custom-sized VPC, subnets, NAT, EC2 instances, ELB and Security groups.
- Automation of Kubernetes native PAAS platform using python boto3 and terraform
- Endorsing technological advancements and maximizing operational efficiency
- Experienced in working as a Platform Engineer /
 DevOps Engineer within an agile organization and
 demonstrated ability to use tools like AWS,
 Kubernetes, Docker, CI/CD, Python, Ansible, and
 Terraform to build robust, scalable, and user-focused
 solutions.
- Always ready to take ownership of work from understanding the requirements to implementation, testing, and maintenance. (End to End)
- Implemented SRE capabilities across all verticals to get more insights into applications
- SRE practice through daily scrum with the Product owner, Engineer, Architects, Developer, Operator, and Scrum Master tracking SRE onboarding in JIRA
- Experienced in the architecture and engineering of secure and reliable hybrid cloud-oriented solutions between (AWS & On-Prem) leveraging the

Work experience

DevSecOps paradigm (i.e. Terraform, Docker, Kubernetes, etc.)

- Capability of solving complex problem challenges with an automation-first approach Cloud Platforms
- Work closely with development teams to diagnose performance, reliability, and security issues in applications and system design
- Using Helm Chart Museum for Production Deployments on EKS using multiple deployment strategies
- Working within small highly collaborative Agile teams with their short-release cycles

Ħ 07/2018 - 04/2021 ♥ NOIDA, INDIA

Senior DevOps Engineer HCL Technology Pvt Ltd

- Defined and scoped cloud and platform consulting engagements
- Led client discovery sessions to understand business needs
- Conducted workshops with clients to assess cloud and platform requirements
- Presented findings and recommendations to clients
- Implemented cloud and platform innovative solutions for example running compute workload on green energy
- Developing ML based planform to run Tensorflow workloads.
- Finding new solution on cloud AWS, GCP to automate remidiate compliance issues
- Monitored and managed cloud and platform implementations for clients
- Devloping serverless framework for different verticals.

DevOps Engineer Atem Corp Pvt Ltd

- Experience in day to day support for code build/deploy and availability of the SDLC environments.
- Experience in configuration and deployments of application in **kubernetes cluster**
- Experience is Infra automation (PaaS) through Terraform
- Hands on experience with DevOps automation tools like **Docker, Ansible.**
- Expertise in working with different Bug Tracking

Work experience

Tools like JIRA, Confluence

- Experience is using **Tomcat**, **JBOSS** and **WebLogic Application** servers for deployments.
- Experience in using Version Control Tools like bitbucket and **Git**.
- Experience in working on AWS and its services like AWS IAM, VPC, EC2, RDS, S3, ELB, Auto Scaling, Route 53, Cloud Watch, Cloud Trail, SQS, SNS,Code Commit,Code Deploy,Code Build Code Pipeline and create custom sized VPC, subnets, NAT, EC2 instances, ELB and Securitygroups.
- Managed Data backup and archiving on AWS using S3.
- Served as a project team lead on large sized technical projects and provided solutions to technical problems of moderate scope and complexity requiring evaluation.
- Integrated multiple Partner to connect Payments bank API.
- Extensive experience with software builds tools like **Apache Maven**, **Apache Ant**.
- Extensive experience in automation using UNIX Shell scripting,
- Hands on experience in upgrading servers using RPM, Apt-get and Yum package installer.
- Experience and understanding of Application Infrastructure (servers, load balancers, web application firewalls).
- Designed end to end automation of infrastructure and continuous delivery of the applications by integrating scripts, Jenkins and Ansible Playbook
- Designing custom workflows for automating the infrastructure.

 ₩ 08/2016 - 12/2016
 ♥ DELHI, INDIA

System Administrator Aspen Communication Pvt. Ltd.

- Develop and maintain configuration management solutions to automate the task by using puppet.
- Tuning performance and ensure high availability of infrastructure.
- Design and develop infrastructure monitoring and reporting tools for Linux, network and security.
- Monitor network communication and setup security policies (e.g. firewalls and intrusion detection systems.
- Focused on automation integration of monitoring system integrated with configuration management
- Track vulnerabilities and apply appropriate patches and upgrades.

Linux System Engineer CHI Networks Pvt. Ltd.

- Providing support and monitoring all location network for Pepsico. Manage FTP server, mail sever and monitoring server.
- Writing Bash script to install web server, LAMP stack and updating OS patches on scheduled basis.
- Taking backup for servers and working 24X7 Support

Work experience

model.

□ 03/2011 - 09/2014 O DELHI, INDIA
 Linux System Administrator
 INS E Solution Pvt Ltd

Education

世 07/2007 - 03/2011 ⊙ DELHI, INDIA Commerce | BCOM Delhi University

Technical Skills

AWS
Python Programming
Terraform IAAC
Linux
GCP



Certificates

Kubernetes

Certified Kubernetes Security Specialist

Certified Kubernetes Application Developer

Certified Kubernetes Administrator

AWS Certified Solutions Architect – Associate

Terraform Associate

RedHat Certified Virtualization Administrator

Red Hat Certified Engineer

GCP Associate Cloud Engineer Certification